Guide to the Russ Meyer collection, 1954-1979.
Meyer, Russ collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Russ Meyer collection, 1954-1979.
8562
Meyer, Russ,
.6 cubic feet (14 items).
Manuscripts, photographs, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Screenplays, publicity posters, and photographs for erotic and exploitation films directed by Russ Meyer. Includes a press kit for the film "Beneath the Valley of the Ultravixens" (1979) and the original pilot script for "The Pornies of Payton Junction" by Martin Winkler (1969). Included are screenplays for "The Desperate Women" (written by Samuel Newman), "Supervixens" (written by Meyer), "Beyond the Valley of the Dolls" (written by Roger Ebert), "Briefing for a Descent Into Hell" (written by Rik Friday), "Beneath the Valley of the Ultravixens" (written by Meyer together with R. Hyde, aka Roger Ebert), and "Vixen!" (written by Meyer; actress Erica Gavin's copy, with her annotations).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
American film director, producer, screenwriter, cinematographer, film editor, actor, and photographer. He is known mainly for writing and directing a series of successful sexploitation films, such as "Faster, Pussycat! Kill! Kill!"
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Screenplays, publicity posters, and photographs for erotic and exploitation films directed by Russ Meyer. Includes a press kit for the film "Beneath the Valley of the Ultravixens" (1979) and the original pilot script for "The Pornies of Payton Junction" by Martin Winkler (1969). Included are screenplays for "The Desperate Women" (written by Samuel Newman), "Supervixens" (written by Meyer), "Beyond the Valley of the Dolls" (written by Roger Ebert), "Briefing for a Descent Into Hell" (written by Rik Friday), "Beneath the Valley of the Ultravixens" (written by Meyer together with R. Hyde, aka Roger Ebert), and "Vixen!" (written by Meyer; actress Erica Gavin's copy, with her annotations).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Meyer, Russ, 1922-2004.; Ebert, Roger,; Friday, Rik,; Gavin, Erica, 1949- ,; Meyer, Russ, 1922-2004,; Meyer, Russ, 1922-2004,; Meyer, Russ, 1922-2004,; Winkler, Martin, active 1969,
Subjects:
Erotic films.; Pornographic films.
Form and Genre Terms:
Screenplays.; Posters.; Press kits.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- The Pornies of Payton Junction, by Martin Winkler (first edition), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Beyond the Valley of the Dolls, color keybook contact sheet (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Beyond the Valley of the Dolls, original screenplay, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beneath the Valley of the Ultra-Vixens, original screenplay, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Russ Meyer press photograph, talking about The Supervixens, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Russ Meyer directing The Supervixens, photo from the set, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Supervixens, original screenplay, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Desperate Women (No Deadlier Sin), original screenplay with original pressbook, ca. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Vixen... the female fox, original screenplay, Erica Gavin's working copy, ca. 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Briefing for a Descent into Hell, original screenplay, first script, ca. 1980's (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Briefing for a Descent into Hell, original screenplay, second script, ca. 1980's (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mudhoney, pressbook, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Faster Pussycat! Kill! Kill!, pressbook, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- How Much Loving Does a Normal Couple Need? (Common Law Cabin), 4 original lobby cards, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Vixen... the female fox, envelope with article about Russ Meyer stapled to back, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Beneath the Valley of the Ultra-Vixens, press kit with 6 photographs, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Beneath the Valley of the Ultra-Vixens, poster, 1979 (Map-case Folder 1)